# MUHAMMAD SHAMEER M

#### **UI DEVELOPER**

## **ABOUT ME**

I am versatile UI Developer with 4 years and 2 month of experience in the design, development and management of complex web applications. I am skilled in **UX / UI Designing, HTML, CSS, JavaScript** and **React JS**. I am a strong engineering professional with a master's degree focused in Computer Application from University of Calicut.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **UI DEVELOPER**

Neointeraction Designs, Bengaluru, India / May 2016 - Present

- Accepted full-time position as UI developer.
- Developed prototypes and high-quality mockups for clients to ensure quality control and client satisfaction before project development phase.
- Used Component Driven Development (CDD) approach to develop and maintain complex web components using React and StoryBook.
- Developed fully functional responsive applications based on Business Requirements using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript while taking advantage of the frameworks like ReactJS.
- Performed cross-browser testing, debugging, website maintenance and enhancements.
- Worked onsite as UI Engineer with a development team for a reputed company in Indonesia.

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**

Freelance, Palakkad, India / October 2015 – May 2016

- Designed and developed fully functional responsive websites for clients using HTML, CSS, JQuery and PHP.
- Performed cross-browser testing and debugging.
- Performed website maintenance and enhancements.

## PERSONAL

Single, Male, 18 June 1991

- mshameer237@gmail.com
- 7012860484, 8884771092
- #101, first floor, 33rd Main, Dollars Scheme Colony, 1st Stage, BTM Layout, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560068,
- in linkedin.com/in/shameerm

## **SKILLS**

Coding: HTML5, CSS3,

JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap,

SASS, React, Material-UI,

StoryBook, Git, React-Native,

Expo, TypeScript

Design: Adobe XD, Sketch,

InVision, Axure.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **MCA**

Calicut University, 2012 - 2015

**BSc. Computer Science** 

BharathiarUniversity 2009 - 2012